Guide to the Margot Gayle Papers 1959-2005 MS 241
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Daily News Columns and Related Materials
  - Plaza Hotel, 1987 June 28 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 24)
  - Sixth Ave. and 49th St, 1987 July 5 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 25)
  - Duryea House, 1987 July 12 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 26)
  - Madison Ave. and 100th St., 1987 July 19 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 27)
  - Catholic School - East 14th St., 1987 August 2 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 28)
  - Montague St. between Court St. and Clinton St., 1987 August 23 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 29)
  - Sulgrave Hotel, 1987 August 30 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 30)
  - St. John's Episcopal Church, 1987 September 20 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Old Main Post Office, 1987 October 4 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
  - Peck Slip, 1987 October 11 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
  - Leggatt House, 1987 October 18 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
  - Samler House, 1987 November 1 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
  - St. James Hotel, 1987 November 8 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hell's Kitchen, 1987 November 22 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Vanderbilt House - Staten Island, 1987 December 6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bowling Green, 1988 January 17 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dry Dock Savings Bank, 1988 February 7 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Erasmus Hall, 1988 February 14 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
  - St. Bartholomew's Church, 1988 April 10 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
  - Jackson Heights Victory Garden, 1988 April 24 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Margot Gayle's New York", 1988 May 1 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
  - Bedford Corners, 1988 May 22 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
  - 3 East 83rd St., 1988 May 29 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 16)
  - Times Building, 1988 June 12 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 17)
  - Dyckman House, 1988 June 19 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 18)
  - "The Permanent Collection", 1988 August 7 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 19)
  - Washington's Statue at Union Square, 1988 August 14 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 20)
  - Cows on Lexington Ave., 1988 August 21 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 21)
  - Academy of Music, 1988 September 11 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 22)
  - Little Church Around the Corner, 1988 September 18 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 23)
  - Garibaldi Memorial - Staten Island, 1988 September 25 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 24)
  - Storm House, Bayside, 1988 October 16 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 25)
  - New York Yacht Club, 1988 October 23 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 26)
  - 183 Broadway, 1988 October 30 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 27)
  - Lafayette Place, 1988 November 6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 28)
  - Brooklyn City Hall, 1988 November 13 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 29)
  - Singer Building, 1988 November 20 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 30)
  - Stuyvesant Flats, 1988 December 4 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 31)
  - Riverdale, 1989 January 1 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
  - Waldorf Hotel, 1989 January 8 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
  - St. John's Chapel and Park Ave., 1989 February 5 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
  - State St. Federal Houses, 1989 February 26 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
  - John Hope General Store, 1989 March 5 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sixth Ave. El Station at 14th St., 1989 March 19 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
  - 16 and 18 High St., 1989 April 23 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Abbott Redux", 1989 April 30 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
  - H. A. Wade House, 1989 May 7 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
  - Church of the Disciples, 1989 June 11 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
  - Workshops on Hudson St., 1989 June 18 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
  - Stewart Mansion, 1989 July 9 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 12)
  - Arc Street Lights - 79th and Broadway, 1989 August 6 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 13)
  - Howard House, 1989 September 10 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 14)
  - Crocheron Farmhouse - Staten Island, 1989 October 1 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 15)
  - First El Tracks - Greenwich St., 1989 October 8 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 16)
  - All Souls Church, 1989 October 22 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 17)
  - Fifth Ave. and 42nd St., 1989 October 29 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 18)
  - Broadway and 242nd St., 1989 December 3 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 19)
  - Old Steinway Piano Factory, 1989 December 31 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 20)
  - Old Livery Stable, 1990 February 4 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 21)
  - Morris-Jumel Mansion, 1990 February 18 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 22)
  - Bell Mansion - Bayside, Queens, 1990 February 25 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
  - Netherland and Savoy Hotels, 1990 April 29 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
  - Rulef Van Brunt House - Brooklyn, 1990 May 6 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
  - Old New York Times Building, 1990 May 13 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn Savings Bank, 1990 May 20 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fifth Ave. and 23rd St., 1990 May 27 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hall of Records, 1990 July 15 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - Produce Exchange, 1990 July 22 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
  - New-York Historical Society, 1990 August 12 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
  - Flatbush Reformed Dutch Church, 1990 August 19 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
  - Mount Prospect/Carnegie Hill, 1990 November 4 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hudson St. and Bank St. - Greenwich Village, 1990 November 25 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
  - Brown's Carriage Factory - Staten Island, 1990 December 2 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bodine Castle, 1990 December 16 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 14)
  - Devlin's Tailoring Establishment, 1991 January 13 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 15)
  - Tammany Hall, 1991 January 27 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hamilton Grange, 1991 February 17 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 17)
  - Jackson Heights Tennis Clubhouse, 1991 May 12 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 18)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Correspondence, Clippings, late 1980s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Research, 1980s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Preservation League of New York State Newsletter Article and Supporting Research, 1987 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Photograph File, late 1980s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: National Park Service Correspondence, 1987 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Letters to the Landmarks Preservation Committee (LPC) and Committee Resolution, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Notes on LPC Hearing, 1988 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: Gayle's Journal Entries on Campaign to Landmark Building, Correspondence, and Clippings, late 1980s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
  - 90 Maiden Lane: "Extra Copies", late 1980s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
- Series II: Subject Material
  Likely preserved for future columns (though Gayle's ultimate intentions remain unclear), subject material files kept by Gayle are arranged alphabetically. Comprised of notes, clippings, and correspondence, they focus on her preservationist efforts.
  - 1008 Fifth Ave., undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Allen Bozeman, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Associates of the Art Commission, Inc., undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
  - Association for Preservation Technology Bulletin, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
  - Augustus Saint-Gaudens, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Heights, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
  - Canal St. - SoHo, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Hall, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cast Iron Bridges - Central Park, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
  - Cast Iron Eagles, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cast Iron Hitching Posts, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
  - Central Park Gates - Christo, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
  - Chelsea Historic District, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
  - City Hall, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
  - Con Edison, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
  - Daily News Financial Records, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
  - Daily News Letterhead, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
  - Daily News Rejections, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Edison Pearl St. Station, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
  - Eighth Regiment Armory, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
  - Empire State Building, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
  - Far Rockaway, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
  - Fine Arts Federation, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
  - Frederick Law Olmsted, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
  - Friends of the Upper East Side Historic District, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
  - George Washington Bridge, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
  - Grand Hotel, undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14)
  - Greenwich Village, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
  - Grover & Baker, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - Harvey Zucker, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jackson Heights, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson Market Area, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
  - Landmarks Conservancy, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
  - Library of Congress Research Materials, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
  - Library of Congress Photo Duplicates, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
  - "Little Red Schoolhouse" - Brooklyn, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Long Island Historical Society, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lucy Moses Award, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
  - Manhattan, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
  - Manhattan Valley Viaduct, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
  - Masonic Temple, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14)
  - Metal in America's Historic Buildings, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 15)
  - Murray Hill, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 16)
  - National Historic Landmarks, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 17)
  - Necessary Luxury Company, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 18)
  - New York Life Insurance Co., undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 19)
  - Peter Cooper Statue at Cooper Union, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 20)
  - Preservation Briefs, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 21)
  - Photo Possibilities, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
  - Prospect Park Boathouse, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
  - Riverside Church, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
  - Robert Wagner, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller Center, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
  - Seventh Regiment Army, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
  - Society for Cast-Iron Architecture, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7)
  - Society for Industrial Architecture, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
  - SoHo, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
  - St. Mark's Church, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 10)
  - State Capitols, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
  - Statue of Justice - City Hall, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
  - Street Lamps, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
  - Street Name Backgrounds, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
  - Subway/Mass Rapid Transit, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
  - Tompkins Square Park, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
  - Twenty-Third Street Association, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
  - Tudor City, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
  - Upper East Side Historic District, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
  - Victorian Society in America, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
  - Wilson Building, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
  - Yankee Clipper, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
- Series III: Publications
  Publications are arranged alphabetically by title. Comprised of books, pamphlets, and other similar materials, this group of publications document buildings and areas in which Margot Gayle was interested; as such, she annotated the vast majority of them.
  - 42nd Street: River to River, 1984 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Alexander Avenue Revitalization, 1976 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Architects in Practice: New York City, 1840-1900, 1980 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Architectural and Decorative Features of St. Bartholomew's Church in the City of New York, 1956 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Architecture: Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries, 1963, 1958 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Behind the Skyline: A Pictorial Study of Downtown New York, 1938 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Blizzard of 1888 Centennial, 1988 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Central Park Prospect Park: A New Perspective, 1985 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Church of the Incarnation Restoration Appeal, 1989 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Churchyards of Trinity Parish in the City of New York, 1955, 1948 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Civic Center Committee Report, 1962 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - A Complete Guide to New York City Including Westchester County and Long Island, 1952 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - The Custom House New York, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Directory of Manhattan Office Buildings, 1978 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - A Dream Fulfilled: City and Suburban's York Avenue Estate, 1988 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - The Empire State Building, 1975 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Father Duffy Square Monuments: Preliminary Report and Conservation Proposal, 2005 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - The Fine Arts Federation of New York, 1979 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Firefighting Museum of the Home Insurance Company, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Four Literary-Historical Walks, 1982 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - The Governor's Room: City Hall, New York, 1982 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Greenwich Village: A Brief Architectural and Historical Guide with Illustrations and a Walking Tour Map, 1976 edition (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Greenwich Village: A Brief Architectural and Historical Guide with Illustrations and a Walking Tour Map, 1981 edition (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Guide to Historical Sites of New York City, 1980 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - A Guide to New York City Landmarks, 1979 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - An Historic District in Murray Hill, 1977 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Historical Report for the Restoration of Bowling Green Park, 1973 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - A History of Building Types, 1976 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - I Love New York Harlem Travel Guide, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Illustrated Guide Book with Historical Sketch of Church of the Transfiguration, 1963 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Inside 42nd Street: An Exhibition of Architecture and Decoration on 42nd Street, 1978 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - John Street Methodist Church, 1966 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Manhattan Block by Block: A Street Atlas, 2000 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - The Men Who Made Central Park, 1982 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Miller's New Guide to Central Park, 1872 (Offsite-box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - New York Advancing: World's Fair Edition, 1939 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - New York: The City that Belongs to the World, 1956 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The New York City Story, 1963 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The New York City Waterfront Comprehensive Planning Workshop, 1974 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - New York Civic Center, 1962 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - New York Landmarks Conservancy News Year 1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Nineteenth-Century New York: Drawings from the Edward C. Arnold Collection of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1970 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Old Streets, Lanes, Piers and Wharves of New York, 1882 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Pearl St., 1982 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Picture Book of Rockefeller Center, 1947 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Planning the Future of New York City: A Conference Celebrating the 40th Anniversary of the New York City Planning Commission, 1979 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Planning and Zoning New York City: Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow, 1992 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Proceedings of the New York State Capitol Symposium, 1981 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Prudential Savings Bank Presents Old New York, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Report to the City of New York Department of Traffic on Traffic, Circulation and Related Studies in the New York Civic Center, 1962 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Riverside Park Map and Guide, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Rockefeller Center Properties, Inc.: 1992 Annual Report, 1993 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Rockefeller Center Properties, Inc.: 1994 Annual Report, 1995 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - South Houston Industrial Area: A Report and Program by the New York City Planning Commission, 1963 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - South Street Seaport Museum Sidewalk Talk, 1977 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The Story of Woodlawn Cemetery, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - St. Bartholomew's Church: Park Avenue, New York, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - St. Patrick's Cathedral: A Centennial History, 1979 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Surrogate's Court/Hall of Records: A Public Treasure, 1991 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Tammany Hall, 1928 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Three St. Bartholomew's: An Architectural History of a Church by David Lowe with an Appeal for its Preservation by Margot Gayle, 1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Tribeca Guide 2000, 1999 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Tribeca Historical Aspects, 1974 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Trinity Church/St. Paul's Chapel, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Turn West on 23rd, 1965 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Union Square Street Revitalization, 1976 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The Unknown Worshipper: The Story of a Sanctuary on Fifth Avenue, the Famous Church of the Open Door-Over a Century of New York Life in and around Washington Square, 1964 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Upper East Side Historic District Designation Report, 1981 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The U.S. Custom House on Bowling Green, 1976 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Village Views: Rockefeller Center: The Decision, 1999 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - A Walk through South Street in the Afternoon of Sail, 1967 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - A Walking Tour of Midtown New York, undated (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Where They Lit Up New York: A Walking Tour Through Thomas Edison's "First District", 1980 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Where They Lit Up New York: A Walking Tour Through Thomas Edison's "First District": Centennial Edition, 1982 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - The Years of Grace 1808-1958 (Offsite-box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - Grand Central Terminal 75th Anniversary 1913-1988 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - Greenwich Village Historic District, 1969 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - A Master Plan for a New Pennsylvania Station, [1998] (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - A Plan for Manhattan Civic Center, 1948 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - Plan for New York City: Introduction and Summary, 1969 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - Rebuilding Central Park: A Management and Restoration Plan, 1985 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
  - Urban Design Manhattan, 1969 (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)
- Series IV: Visual Materials
  Visual materials include photos, stereographs, reproductions of photographs, slides; they are arranged in order of relative importance to the collection as a whole and focus on buildings and street scenes.
  - Photographs and Negatives (includes Pan Am Construct), [1961-1963] (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Lower Manhattan, East Village, 4 July 1961 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
  - Photographs Courtesy of Allen and Hilary Weiner received by Gayle in 1976 - Old NYC, late 1800s (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
  - Photographs received by Gayle in 1976 - Scenes of NYC, late 1800s (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
  - Professional Photographs - New York Streets and Buildings (Early), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - NYC Buildings, Courtesy of Dorothy Dudley, 1955 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
  - Photographs by Gayle - City Hall, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Outside of City Hall, MLK Memorial Walk, April 5, 1968 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 8)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Moving George Washington Statue from the Metropolitan Museum of Art to City Hall, 1970 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 9)
  - Photographs by Gayle - World Trade Center Construction, Lower Manhattan, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10)
  - Photographs by Gayle- Sun Building, 280 Broadway (A.T. Stewart), 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 11)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Former Rhinelander Building, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12)
  - Photographs and Negatives by Gayle - Lower Manhattan Construction of Pace College Annex and Beekman Hospital Annex, 1966-1968 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 13)
  - Photographs by Gayle- Washington Market Area, 1968 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Notes - Moving of McComb House, Washington Market Area, 1970 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 15)
  - Photographs by Gayle - 9th Street/4th Avenue, Old Stuyvesant House, May-August 1969 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
  - Photographs by Gayle - 6th Avenue, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Madison Avenue and 60th Street, 1969 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Harlem, 1961 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Demolition: Old Astor Hotel, Republican Alley, and East 13th Street, 1960s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Demolition: Singer Building and Unknown, 1968 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
  - Photographs by Gayle - Manhattan Demolition and Construction, late 1960s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
  - Photographs for Potential Daily News Columns, 1960s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
  - Slides, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9)
  - Negatives - City Hall Park, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 10)
  - Negatives - New York Streets, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 11)
  - Stereoscopes, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 12)
  - Photographic Reproductions, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
  - Stereoscope Reproductions, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
  - Negatives, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 15)
  - Negatives, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
  - Photographs and Negatives of "USA Town 2", 1968 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - NAACP Gathering (Mayor's Reception), May 1962 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and Negatives - "People", 1960s (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Nippon Maru Cadets, 1960 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and Negatives of United Kingdom, 1967 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Philadelphia and Washington, D.C., May and June 1969 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - Other Cities, 1968 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
  - Notes, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Bristol Building, undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder unknown container)